Gleb Polushkin

Software Engineer at Akvelon

gleb.proll@gmail.com

Summary

12+ years of professional experience in web development. I'm a passionate and self-motivated front-end developer and I pay a lot attention to latest Javascript and browsers trends as SPA, Virtual DOM. Not only concentrating on the technical part of the job, but also on the process and reaching the project's goals.

Beloved conceptions: HTML5 and its gorgeous APIs, CSS3, LESS/Stylus, Vanilla JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, BackboneJS, React, Git, Grunt, NodeJS, W3C, progressive enhancement, mobile browser optimisation and continuous integration technics.

Experience

Software Engineer at Akvelon

November 2015 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Akvelon was founded in 2000 to provide superior IT consulting and software development services. Akvelon's clients range from tiny start-ups to global corporations.

- Work as contractor for Reddit on Reddit Desktop and Audiences projects.
- Automate testing workflow with Akvelon Testing framework integration.
- Worked as contractor for Microsoft on Microsoft Power BI project.
- Automated and refactored review process of Custom Visuals for Microsoft Power Bi Custom Visuals gallery.
- Developed validation tool for Power BI Custom Visuals which validates packages and checks source code for potential insecure javascript and harmful css with NodeJS, Gulp, ESLint, StyleLint, PostCSS, TSLint.
- Developed publication software for Power BI Custom Visuals Gallery, developed on Azure Cloud Storage API using NodeJS.
- Developed Power BI CDN content checker tool using ReactJS and WebPack.

Senior Front-end developer at Lazada Group

June 2015 - November 2015 (6 months)

Lazada is Southeast Asia's No. 1 Online Shopping and Selling Destination. It is Southeast Asia's number one online shopping and selling destination, with presence in Indonesia, Malaysia, Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam. Lazada also has offices in Hong Kong, Korea, United Kingdom and Russia.

- Refactored mobile version for 6 regional Lazada sites (http://lazada.vn , http://lazada.co.id etc.)

- Implemented CSS regression testing tool. It helped with automation testing of releases and increase stability of revamps.
- Implemented ESLint-controlled Javascript code style into the Lazada public site project.
- Implemented multi-sprite builder task inside project Grunt and then Gulp builder for raster and vector (svg) icons.

Achievement

Implemented javascript code styles for 4 multicultural front-end teams which are used today on production development.

Senior Front-end developer at iMobilco

May 2014 - June 2015 (1 year 2 months)

iMobilco is a distributer and a publisher of ebooks, magazines and music.

- Developed and support http://imobilco.ru using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap+LESS, Javascript, Backbone.js +Marionette, lodash.js, handlebars.js.
- Developed proxy server using Node.js and Phantom.js to make Search bot possible to crawl the dynamic SPA sites.
- Developed client proxy to proxy current project page resources from localhost.
- Integrated Google Analytics eCommerce API which turned over service auditory valuation.

Achivement

Refactored front-end building system with NodeJS and Gulp. This decreased build time by 80%.

Senior Front-end developer at WeHeartPics

February 2013 - April 2014 (1 year 3 months)

We Heart Pics is the only fully-functional, photo-powered, social network. They enable people to communicate without relying on a mutual language or location.

- Developed Responsive Mobile-first single-page web applications with templates on client side using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap+LESS, SVG, HTML5 APIs (Canvas API, Geo API), Javascript, BackboneJS, lodash.js, handlebars.js
- Developed build system using NodeJS, Grunt, Imagemagick, UglifyJS, JSHint, CSSMin, HTMLMin, ImageMin, NodeSprite.
- Rewrote Instagram-like Image Open GL ES 2.0 shaders from mobile app to flash AGAL shaders.
- Rewrote Instagram-like Image shaders to Javascript Canvas shader programs working on Webworkers.
- Implemented Microformats and SEO best practices for photos, products, used oEmbed for videos.

Achievement

Developed Responsive Mobile-first SPA with Instagram-like photo filters which helped company to support service on web and made traffic for iOS application higher.

Front-end developer at BigBuzzy.ru

November 2011 - January 2013 (1 year 3 months)

BigBuzzy is a Groupon-like service.

- Applied Mobile-first and Progress Enhancement principles on mobile version of http://bigbuzzy.ru http://bigbuzzy.ru/m/ using modernizer.js, jQuery, lodash.js, CSS3, MediaQueries.
- Rewrote best parts of jQueryMobile for the mobile site.
- Tested the mobile site and made all business goals feasible on a wide row of mobile devices (with Nokia Symbian, Windows Phone, Android 1.6-3.0, IOS)
- Rewrote site templates from XSLT to Freemarker, created template engine of block macros, layout macros, functions and utilities.
- Got a massive expertise in HTML pixel perfect layout according to W3C standards.
- Developed layout builder for email newsletters with HTML4.

Achievement

Created progress-enhancement-based mobile and refactored desktop sites on my new FTL template engine showed 100x decrease of server response time and raised profit of the company by 16%.

Front-end Team Lead at SM & Partners

December 2008 - November 2011 (3 years)

SM & Partners is a development company. Creation and Accompaniment high-load web projects like business-oriented social networking services, dating and hr networking services.

- Developed RPG in-browser game for kids using Javascript, jQuery, CSS, ActionScript, PHP, MySQL.
- Created and debugged internet browser based on Firefox with a parental control extension on XUL.
- Architected server software for fast pre-rendering and rendering animations of game characters using Python and Blender3D
- Developed service for accounting game character outfits and animations with PSD parsing, management of artist's works, and XML configs generation using Javascript, jQuery, psd.js, NodeJS, PHP, MySQL, imagemagick
- Developed the video encoder software system on FFMPEG and PHP as module of blog social network http://f5.ru

Achievement

Architected, Developed and Managed whole product from the scratch - Social RPG in-browser game for kids (http://boodoo.ru) as a Team Lead of the 8 members team.

Web Developer at Mediatoday

March 2008 - December 2008 (10 months)

Mediatoday is a full-service digital agency

- Developed imdb-like web project with pages for movies, movietheatres, schedules, people from movie industry and ratings for all this. http://filmtoday.ru is now closed.
- Developed back-end for online reservation ticket system with PHP, MySQL and automated bot system which synchronizes schedule and supports reservation ticket system.
- Developed front-end part of the service using HTML4, CSS2, Javascript, jQuery and Papervision3d.

Achievement

My work helped this site became second most visited project about movies in Russia in 2008 (http://afisha.ru, http://filmtoday.ru).

Web Developer at BellIntegrator

October 2005 - March 2008 (2 years 6 months)

Bell Integrator is a global consulting, technology services, and outsourcing company that offers business critical solutions that resolve your most complex IT and business needs for top-tier telecom, finance, transportation, and healthcare enterprises.

- Developed the graphic charts modules (plain tree chart with the backpack algorithm and other trees, pies, bars etc.) for monitoring systems.
- Got experience in Javascript, Actionscript and enterprise development.

Achievement

Developed aggregating algorithms allowed to display really big data on slow client's machines.

Publications

2.5D games and feature of multiplayer game development

Highload++ Conference October 28, 2010

Authors: Gleb Polushkin

It's my report for Highload++ Conference 2010 - a review of servers and client technologies plus frameworks for multiplayer browser games. There I presented SmartFox Server as the best solution for that time.

Mobile Front-end development blog

http://blog.prolll.com/

Authors: Gleb Polushkin

My blog in Russian is about Mobile Front-end development. Quite often I need to write down and share an unknown mobile browser feature so this blog is designed for this.

Projects

Qstoq.me

May 2013 to September 2014

Members: Gleb Polushkin, Dmitry Shilyaev, Vladimir Gorshkov

Get payments online for what ever and where ever you want

Qstoq — it is a platform for creating price tags and getting payments for your digital content or real goods and services

Front-end is based on Backbone.JS, Bootstrap+LESS, handlebars.

Back-end Qstoq RESTful API is based on PHP, Yii and MySQL.

Small pitch about our API

http://www.slideshare.net/dsqstoq/qstoq-bs04

stylogram.com

January 2013 to January 2014

Members: Gleb Polushkin, Dmitry Kozachenok

Boston, USA based startup project with an idea of the personal fashion advisers from the USA for russian woman.

Front-end is based on backbone.js, bootstrap+less.

Back-end is PHP and MySQL.

boodoo.ru

December 2008 to November 2011

Members: Gleb Polushkin, Serge Kuzmenko

Social network for kids and browser with parent control

Certifications

Developing Innovative Ideas for New Companies: The First Step in Entrepreneurship

Coursera April 2014

Google Analytics Platform Principles

Google License fc7fe77b83034f0cb2ca4acd7f4d447b March 2014

Startup Engineering

Coursera September 2013

MCTS Microsoft SQL Server

2007

Languages

English

Russian

(Professional working proficiency) (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

JavaScript

Backbone.js

React

jQuery

jQuery Mobile

Node.js

HTML5

CSS

LESS

Stylus

SASS

SVG

Web Applications

MySQL

Web Standards

PHP

AGAL

Freemarker

AMD

LMD

Git

JSON

XML

Front-end

Typescript

D3.js

Handlebars.js

Jade

Education

Vyatka State Technical University

Master's Degree, Computer Science, 2000 - 2005

Interests

Entrepreneurship, GFX, New Technologies

Gleb Polushkin

Software Engineer at Akvelon

gleb.proll@gmail.com



2 people have recommended Gleb

"I've been working with Gleb as Developer Relations Manager in Lazada Group for more than 6 months. Working together Gleb he has demonstrated both high quality refactoring of our legacy code base and writing high quality code from the scratch. As a top notch web developer Gleb has helped to improve our core framework and shared his deep knowledge with other web-developers. He is self-motivated and reliable expert who is always up to date with all updates in the area of JS, BackboneJS, ReactJS, SPA and other front-end trends. We are Mobile First company and Gleb has helped us to achieve enormous progress by his commitment in mobile browsing experience of our customers."

— Alexander Ptitsyn, Employee Relations Manager, Lazada Group, worked directly with Gleb at Lazada Group

"I worked with Gleb on BigBuzzy, Imobilco and Iphones.ru. The results were always great. He's one of those professionals who really stand for the project — with great attention to detail and perfectionism in a good way. Gleb's huge expertise in modern frontend helps him to find great and practical solutions for any development challenge we encounter. When he works on a project, I'm confident that its frontend part will be all right. And he's a great team player —always open and helpful. His valuable advice on anything about web development supported me countless times."

— **Denis Drozhzhov**, Art Director, Bigbuzzy, worked directly with Gleb at BigBuzzy.ru

Contact Gleb on LinkedIn